<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Esoteric Rapture</title>
        <description>Ameliorate Consciousness</description>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self"
        type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 00:14:54 +0530</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2018 00:14:54 +0530</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v3.7.3</generator>
        
        <item>
            <title>Listen...</title>
            <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;listen&quot;&gt;Listen…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winds are howling with pain alongside me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somewhere, an old violin tears up as it sings the most desolate tunes one has ever heard. And&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then I…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a painter, etching colours on the canvas of my body, wine red spilling from my black lips as they etch on my feverish skin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shudder. The moon frowns at me through the windows of my room as I feebly try to raise my hand. It attempts but it falls, it is tired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like you who would always prefer to stay under the warm lights of my room, sheltering in music and love as you bottled me up inside your&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;soul and heart. I gaze pitifully at the reflections of the glass shards that gaze back at me; Oh, you wouldn’t have liked to see this mess&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;at all. No, you wouldn’t. Just like you couldn’t have just walked through the door now. .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am crying with pain; one of the shards sticking out of my foot, my red blood mixing with the ambient maroon of my drink; the painting is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;being completed in front of my very eyes. I lie on the floor, hungover and miserable. You didn’t have to leave, you know. Because this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;isn’t how it usually goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I leave, then you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this… This reversal is insanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pain beyond measure to see a part of myself aching to be with a phantom, gone. .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hands shake as I pound the table beside me. Something heavy falls, splashing on the pool of red.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A necklace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A last reminder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one which I had surprised you with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You didn’t even take it with you…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colorless drops join the ever moving fluid of shades as they settle on the object that mourns its existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I blink my eyes, my vision blurry as I now pick up the bloodied necklace from the paints of my blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I crawl near the window as I hold my prize up to the moon, the eternal canvas, it glitters; it’s red shades tearfully gazing at me, upset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For what was a man without his dear beloved?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whose neck shall not adore the pretty bloodied necklace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As both man and muse sit under the glowing moon&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly waiting… for either to die. .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~Abhiruk B. .&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2018 17:42:12 +0530</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000#/2018/03/09/listen.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000#/2018/03/09/listen.html</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The wrath of an outlier</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;” The child who is not embraced by the village will burn it down to feel its warmth. “&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;- African Proverb&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an intriguing proverb which has filled me with mystery and insights. I want to unravel this overawing subtlety. Man is a social animal. Abondenment is a suffering for him. Let it be a single person, but he needs someone. While being social, he has adopted the preconceived notions of the herd mentality. As he follows those principles and idelogies, he expects that the others should follow them as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If a person is an outlier or an outlaw, the society abondens him, makes him suffer through isolation. They have a pseudo-purpose behind this prejudice. They think an outlier is a danger for the society as he has the potential to disrupt their preconceived notions. Deep down, subconsciously they are jealous and envious about his true self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The outliers who learn to enjoy this solitude go on to live a blissful life. The more the outlier suffers, the more the society tortures and dominates him. He must be courageous enough to ignore the noise and feel the euphoria of silence. The outlier goes through three stages of an intense emotional tycoon before reaching the so called elysium: fear, anger, silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Initially, he is horrorified by their tantrums andthe feeling of being a “misfit”. He undertakes ceaseless endeavours to fit in the so caled moral norms of the society but experiences a great misery in the process. After feeling shattered, something else replaces this fear: the wrath of anger. In the heat of the moment, the extremely provoked outlier goes on to   &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;burn down the village&lt;/strong&gt;. In that moment, he’s the omnipotent dominant entity. The smirk has now disappeared from the members of the society. The self-righteous tyrants are now the perplexed cowards who are astonished by the rebellious act of the misfit which they never anticipated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The wrath of anger and fury slowly fades away. With the complete disapperance of this fury, the misfit is burdened by guilt. His soul is eaten by his conscience. As he contemplates over this situation in retrospect, he realises that he was driven by his rage which made him do the things which he’ll never do when he’s conscious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the milestone where an epiphany occurs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Baskerville font-size: 24px&quot;&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Smiling gazing at the moon...&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;An epiphany occured,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Roses are made of diamonds...&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;A diamond can cherish the mood&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;but a rose cannot cure the gloom?&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;-Rohit Naidu&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moment he starts enjoying the solitude is the moment he becomes the resident of elysium and utopia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Einstein is known to have quoted:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Solitude is painful in youth, but fruitful in the years of maturity.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a dog-eat-dog world. Either you dominate you get dominated. It’s just like binary: either you’re zero or one. The African proverb implies an indispensable moral epiphany about it. It provides us insights about the potential of an outlier to disrupt havoc and wreakage if he’s not solaced and embraced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fantastic Beasts &amp;amp; Where To Find Them&lt;/em&gt;, a renowned blockbuster movie based on magic and wizardry illusrates this situation with the help of a concept known as an &lt;em&gt;Obscurus&lt;/em&gt;: When a child is tortured and traumatised beyond measure, all his magical powers gradually turn to have the aura of dark magic. In the end, he’s transformed into an obscurus: A very powerful form of dark arts where one is transformed into an evil, voilent and furious creature whose sole purpose is to cause ceaseless destruction and havoc until it runs out of it’s energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Rohit Naidu&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 17:42:12 +0530</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000#/2018/03/07/rebel.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000#/2018/03/07/rebel.html</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Mumbai Diaries</title>
            <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;mumbai-diaries&quot;&gt;Mumbai Diaries.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it so happens that in one of the most populous cities of the world, you end up realizing at nearly midnight that you don’t have a 
place to crash in. Say shitty friends or a victim of unfortunate circumstances; but at that instance, you know you’re simply… fucked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a lovely feeling when you know that you got a couple of hours to pass on the streets maybe but you being tired from the day doesn’t 
help with things. So, you do the next logical thing.
You take your fat wallet off the jeans and punch and kick it but you know you ain’t got the cash either to rent a fancy room. You know you 
got no other options as your phone’s about to die as well. You look at the sky and you start laughing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s when you look around at the crowd of people around you and you do the “most logical thing”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Hey. I’m visiting the city here for a couple days. Came to tour it you know. Yeah, I shoot around pretty much. Been also writing a book.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And ten minutes later, you’re off with a stranger to his friend’s flat who’s got this rad party going on and you don’t need me to tell that 
where there are parties, there are people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you basically talk, communicate and drink everyone’s favourite rum while being stacked in rooms with bright lights and smoke flying 
around. You find some cute eyes but you decide that it’s better to just stick to the drink for the night. That’s when you meet someone who 
takes you up to be his next best friend and an hour later, you get a nice comfy bed to crash in and fresh herbs from unknown hill stations 
to smoke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have a nice night chatting about the future of the country and how everything’s shitty even though it’s not. You nod along with your 
host as he criticizes the government and then sleep like a log after it; waking up, just in time to catch the last local before your 
precious leg-space is sacrificed. And well, a few hours later with more than a hundred brilliant photographs, you end up on a train back 
home, exhausted yet strangely rejuvenated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So who tells you that you can’t have a hell of a night broke in a large metropolitan city? Because I and Mumbai definitely disagree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Abhiruk B.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 17:42:12 +0530</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000#/2018/03/07/mumbai-diaries.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000#/2018/03/07/mumbai-diaries.html</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Rainbow Boy</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Rainbow Boy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a boy who braids a rainbow of chrysanthemums, my brain a pantheon of spring eternal, and a mansion residing under celluloid, across a thin divide that breaks my gender down and then surrenders every wrong pronoun and stereotype.&lt;br /&gt;
I try to visualise prophets that harmonize cologne and acetone, who choose to carry home a human not defined by chromosome;&lt;br /&gt;
I pick upon my trembling palm, a bud of tingling palm, my pillow warring with demonic holograms;&lt;br /&gt;
a certain magic is cocooned in carving lullabies within balloons; I wash my wounds in shirts of baby pink and corduroys;&lt;br /&gt;
I am a boy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a boy who smells of peppermint and morning brush, and through his dawn and dusk, in saree, reads a cooking omnibus.&lt;br /&gt;
A soaring dominance of condescending glances I receive;&lt;br /&gt;
the ones that highly grieve are launched from staunch assumptions preconceived.&lt;br /&gt;
They hurt, I heal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not my fault I chose a Barbie o’er the Man of Steel; it’s not my fault I like to cook and you forgot your grain of salt;&lt;br /&gt;
it’s not my fault you want to thwart the ways of reason and distort the prison of my sex while you abort my female counterpart;&lt;br /&gt;
and summer laughs in scorn as you respond to normalcy with paragon, and winter sheds a tear as you abuse my friend for his attire.&lt;br /&gt;
And I admire my bequeathed superior place, with an ulterior distate, and you sever in two my brittle, woven braids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pick them up and add them to the relics on my wall. It’s blessed of me to be among the privileged of them all.&lt;br /&gt;
This is me, a boy who braids chrysanthemums in rainbows, and climbs on marshmallow treehouses when he finds the gate closed.&lt;br /&gt;
This is me, who wants to help, but finds his sex disgusting; this is gently rusting drops of twisted lust, and this is hatred thrust into a cup of coffee-brown acceptance, morphine on repentance, tossing out the window effort on effort at independence.&lt;br /&gt;
This is sin dependent on the superintendence of society over us, a sentence ominous to slay variety with dominance;&lt;br /&gt;
supremist vomitus assuming prominence- an octopus of heinous lie that turns a rock to dust- this one’s for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one’s for you, who prays for better morning every night. This one’s for you, who wants to break their shackles of disguise;&lt;br /&gt;
who wants to sanitize their day from judgement that does traumatize; this one’s for you who dreams of living, and then wakes up to survive-   this one’s for life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one’s for life, and people who desire one that’s true. I know you’ll rise, and rainbow boy will love to rise with you.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Aditya Narayan&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 17:42:12 +0530</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000#/2018/02/19/rainbow-boy.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000#/2018/02/19/rainbow-boy.html</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Aphrodite</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Aphrodite&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it’s dark inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;god laughs, she says,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you’re a dork. I say, okay,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but you’re pulling the strings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;here. she smiles at me. some&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;secrets are best swallowed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;straight to your intestines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;she tosses her hair into the sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;night falls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i clutch my abdomen like&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it is a telephone receiver waiting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;to get thrown back&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in its socket. her secret is in,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;my lips feel glued to each other. i&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;look at her with love&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in my eyes, and she sighs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this is heaven, she explains. it&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;doesn’t get better than this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;her eyes are glistening gold,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i almost think&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;she’s about to cry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but gods don’t cry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i think back to the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;time i told her about me. we were&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on the roof, her long legs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dangling from an edge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;winter clouded over our&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;small talk like a commercial&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;that kept the universe entertained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;two weeks later,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the mist had parted, and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;our lips met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i’d never felt so holy before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;love had always felt like a demon,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a cobweb kissing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the left corner of my ribs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for the first time,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i saw my secret bathed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in the pool of an open night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;short. dark-skinned. divine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i want to shake her by the shoulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tell her how some secrets&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;are worth spilling, worth folding into&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;each other’s hearts. i want to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;show her that it’s okay to be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mortal. to feel. but she’s a god.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and gods don’t feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~ Aditya Narayan&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 17:42:12 +0530</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000#/2018/01/06/aphrodite.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000#/2018/01/06/aphrodite.html</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title> A Master &amp; A Disciple</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;&quot;Don't insist upon your own fixed ideas.&lt;br /&gt;
 If your mind is broad it can easily embrace the entire world.&quot;&quot;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
   &lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;- Zen Proverb&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A master is who broadens the vision and strengthens the endurance of a disciple. A master inculcates the discipline essential for the intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a subtle difference between a teacher and a guru. Teacher is just a profession and guru is a way of living. Teacher is of the west and a guru is of the east.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relationship between guru and disciple is intimate like love&lt;/strong&gt;. The reverence that is felt is like love but one difference: love is parallel and reverence is one above the other. Love creates friendship, because the lover and the loved one are on the same level. Reverence is also a kind of love but with a great difference: it is not on he same level, one person is higher. If there’s loving intimacy with the personality above, the reverence is not expected or demanded, but it is automatically created around the guru.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A guru is not aware of his guru-ship. A guru cannot claim that he is a guru. A guru has attended the condition of egolessness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The relationship between the disciple and the guru is a relationship of intimate trust.&lt;/strong&gt; That doesn’t mean blind faith, because the guru never expects you to believe in him — that is not an expectation.  Guru is always saying, “Jump into it! Do it!” But before you can jump, trust is needed or you will not jump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reverence for a teacher is not possible. It is forced, artificial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a guru, it happens automatically in the mind of the disciple. It’s the charisma of the guru which attracts the disciple like gravity. A teacher is knowledgeable but a master is intuitive and meditative. A teacher is ingrained with machine-like monotony.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Even concepts such as beauty are not totally expressible&lt;/strong&gt; 
If you have seen a flower, you can say it is beautiful. But that does not convey anything. Your words never convey the actual realization of the moment because they can mean anything to the person to whom they are conveyed. A person who has never seen beauty in any flower will hear your words and understand the meaning of them without understanding anything at all, because the word beauty does not mean anything to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some indispensable revelations implied in the following poem:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;font-family: Baskerville font-size: 24px&quot;&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;You're a master and I'm your disciple,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Not an instructor not an authority to order&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;But a master who observes, envelopes and loves his disciple&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;The wrath of your grandeur is calamitous&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Conventional wisdom is superficial&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;But your eccentric approach is altruistic&lt;/i&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;The way you teach is fabulous&lt;/i&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;The time spent in your lectures is eternal,&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Time ceased with each of your insightful revelation&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Your talks are esoteric elevating me to the epitome of bliss&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Its my honor to be a disciple of a guru like you.&lt;/i&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;You make me feel bliss and get totally engrossed in learning too.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;-Rohit Naidu&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 17:42:12 +0530</pubDate>
            <link>http://localhost:4000#/2017/09/05/master-disciple.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000#/2017/09/05/master-disciple.html</guid>
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
